Nathaniel Bugeja





nathanielbugeja15@gmail.com



Nathaniel Bugeja



Nathaniel Bugeja



+35679667610



Nathaniel Bugeja



Lisence B

Professional Summary

Aspiring Software Development student that goes above and beyond to contribute to team objectives. Contributes to process optimization by automating tasks for increased efficiency. Aptitude for building client rapport and guiding technical decisions. Experience with Java, Csharp, HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Python through studies. True team player with strengths in adaptability and accuracy.

Resourceful IT Technical Trainer with 2 years of experience tracking IT trends for curriculum inclusion. Lends well-versed approach to presenting engaging, hands-on material. Extensive familiarity breaking down technical concepts and processes. Hands-on development of technology training resources to surpass organization's skill-level expectations. Integration with educational systems to provide best educational content.

Job related Skills

- Team Exercises
- Attention to Detail
- Clear Communication
- Language skills
- Consultation and delegation
- Quality Assurance
- Decision Making
- Coaching and Development

Marketing skills through the running of exhibition Facebook page

Communicative skills from forming part of a football team Problem-solving skills through altercations with parents Time-management skills trough having a two jobs and studies

Good interpersonal skills through completing interpersonal and intrapersonal unit during course

Work History

 IT Trainer / Holistic Institute of technologies - Lija, MT 06/2021 - Current

Oversaw technical documentation, instruction and evaluation to meet IT education initiatives.

Compiled IT training and assessment resources based on understanding of technical processes and skills-development needs.

Led syllabus preparation based on detailed breakdowns of technical concepts.

Blended traditional learning approaches with existing ones.

Acted as first-tier technical helper for students and assisted with answering technical questions.

Technical Assistant / Fgura United F.C - Fgura MT
Jun 2018 - Current

Gathered, organized and distributed technical documentation.

Aiding of Fgura United Facebook page.

Assessed, diagnosed and troubleshot malfunctioning hardware and software devices found in Fgura United club.

Sports Playworker / Skolasajf - Sliema MT

May 2019 - Sep 2019

Creating fun and innovative exercises for young children (3-4 years).

Organizing exciting outings for the students.

Responsibility with allergies or sickness that the students might have.

Carried out day-to-day duties accurately and efficiently. Demonstrated respect, friendliness and willingness to help wherever needed.

Performed duties in accordance with applicable standards, policies and regulatory guidelines to promote safe working environment.

Football Coach - Fgura United F.C - Fgura MT

Jun 2017 - Aug 2021

Evaluated individual knowledge, skills and strengths and assigned team positions to maximize talent areas.

Prepared children for special competitions and tournaments.

Established clear benchmarks for performance and monitored individual and team progress.

Motivated the children to become stronger, more agile and more effective through training habits and proper nutrition.

Education

 MCAST Institute of Information Technology - Paola MT MOF Level 6

10/2018 - Current

Bachelor of Science in Multimedia Software Development https://iict.mcast.edu.mt/

 Latvia University of Life Sciences And Technologies (LLU) -Jelgava Latvia

EQF level 6 | MQF Level 6

02/09/2019 - 20/12/2019

Multimedia Security And Software Development https://www.llu.lv/

• MCAST Institute of Information Technology - Paola MT

MQF Level 4

10/2016 - 05/2018

Advanced Diploma in Multimedia Software Development https://iict.mcast.edu.mt/

St Thomas More Secondary Boys - Hamrun MT
School leaving certificate (Level 3)

2011-2016

Secondary Education and 8 O'Levels

Maths, English, Maltese, Religion, Art, Computer Studies, Environmental Studies, Physics

https://edumalta.gov.mt/en/schools/state-schools/st-thomas-more-college-hamrun-boys-support-learning-centre

 St Thomas More Primary School - Fgura MT 2002-2010

Primary Education

https://edumalta.gov.mt/en/schools/state-schools/st-thom-as-more-college-fgura-primary-a

Projects

Computer Java Coursework Project

Environmental Public Transport Project

Embedded Systems Project using raspberry pi

Entrepreneurship project to develop new technology

Dissertation for course study. (Comparison between DDA (Dynamic Difficulty Adjustment) educational math mobile games: analyzing their effects when implemented in an educational system.)

Quotes

I am thankful for my struggles because without them I wouldn't have come across my strength's (Anon)

You need failure because failure is the stepping stone to success (Anon)